Society for Industrial Microbiology records
Society for Industrial Microbiology records
- Series II. Business Secretary, 1949-1999; bulk 1950-1996; 1,400 items (2.75 linear feet)
  - Subseries II.A. Business Office, 1973-1985; 200 items (.25 linear feet)
    - Policy Manuel 1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Policy Manuel 1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Policy Manuel 1987 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II.B. Membership, 1949-1999; 1,200 items (2.5 linear feet)
    Applications, brochures, ledgers, member lists and Directories, and questionnaires organized in alphabetical order by subject and then in date order.
    - Applications for membership 1957 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Brochures 1968-1981 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Corporate Members No Date Listed (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Ledger Rolls A-K 1950-1957 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Ledger Rolls G-N 1950-1957 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Ledger Rolls O-Z 1950-1957 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Member Lists 1949-1951, 1956, 1958, 1960-1961 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Member Lists 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Member Lists 1983 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Member Lists 1984 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Member Lists 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Member Lists A-L 1999 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Member Lists M-Z 1999 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Member Yearbook 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Printed Directories 1965, 1969, 1972, 1975, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Printed Directories 1983, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Printed Directories 1991, 1994-1995, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Questionnaire (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Series III. Committees, 1952-1996; 1,000 items (1.25 linear feet)
  Correspondence, memos, reports, and rosters organized by name of committee
  - Member Rosters: undated, 1981-1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/Frances Johnson, incoming 1983-1985 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/Frances Johnson, outgoing 1983-1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/Frances Johnson, incoming 1986-1990 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/picture requests 1986 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/V. Lilly 1960-1984 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Archives Committee: Correspondence/ Northwestern University Library 1978-1991 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Archives Committee: Oral History Project (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Archives Committee: Reports for Board Meetings 1983-1990 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Grants Committee: Correspondence 1971-1981 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Awards and Grants Committee: “Charlie Porter” Nominations 1995 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Awards and Grants Committee: “Charles Thom” 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Awards and Grants Committee: Fellowship 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Awards and Grants Committee: “Waksman Outstanding Teaching” 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Education Committee: Correspondence 1961-1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Education Committee: Correspondence 1972/4-1976/4 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Education Committee: 1988-1989, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Local Sections Committee: 1973-1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Membership Committee: 1979, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Membership: Emeritus/Quarter Century Club 1974- 1979 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Nominations: Correspondence 1959-1964 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Nominations: Correspondence 1965-1974 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Placement Committee: 1979 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Planning Committee: 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Policy Manual Committee: Correspondence 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Policy Manual Committee: 1982 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Program Committee: Correspondence 1952, 1961-1963, 1970-1979 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Publications Committee: Correspondence 1971-1978 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Publicity Committee: Correspondence 1975 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Speaker’s Bureau Committee: Correspondence 1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Speaker’s Bureau Committee: Correspondence 1966-1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Summer Institute Committee: Correspondence 1965-1968/5 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Summer Institute Committee: Correspondence 1968/6-1970 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Meetings, 1949-2001; bulk 1960-1993 bulk; 2,600 items; (3.25 linear feet
  Correspondence, minutes, memos, reports, forms, proceedings, papers, programs and photographs arranged into five sub-series: Correspondence, Annual Meetings, Conferences, Symposia and Workshops, Joint Meetings, and Local Chapters.
  - Subseries IV.A. Correspondence, 1949-1971; 250 items (.25 linear feet)
    Correspondence organized in alphabetical order by subject.
    - Conferences/Herman 1960/6-1960/8 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Conferences/Herman 1960/9 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Conferences/Herman 1960/10-1961/3 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Organizational 1949/10-12 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Summer Institute 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV.B. Annual Meetings, 1950-1991; 400 items (1 linear foot)
    Correspondence, reports, minutes, memos, forms, proceedings and photographs arranged in alphabetical order by subject and then in date order.
    - Committee Reports 1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Minutes 1950-1958 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Minutes 1964-1969 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Minutes 1970-1974 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Minutes 1975-1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous memos, reports 1960-1981 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous memos, reports, correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Photographs 1981-1988 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Photographs 1984 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Photographs 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Photographs 1990 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Presentation 1989 (John Howard Video) (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Printed Proceedings 1955-1958 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Registration Reply Forms 1967 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Subseries IV.C. Conferences, Symposia, Workshops, 1960-2001; 55 items (1.75 linear feet)
    Proceedings, programs, papers and memos organized by individual conference, symposia, or workshop with all conferences first followed by all symposia and workshops in date order.
    - Conferences 1960, 1963, 1967, 1990, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Actinomycete Taxonomy 1978 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Freezing and Freeze Drying 1979 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Freezing and Freeze Drying 1980 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Applications of Microbial Protoplasts 1981 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Fungus Tests 1982 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Asepsis in Fermentation 1982 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Plasmids in Biotechnology 1984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Introduction to Chemical Engineering for Microbiologists 1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Interfacing Fermentation with Recombinant DNA Technology 1986 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Process Cooling Water: Problems and Solutions 1987 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Water: Microbiological/Quality Issues 1987 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Biotechnology of Microbial Products 1988 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Fermentation Process Technology: Mammlian and Microbial Cell Culture 1988 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Polymerose Chain Reaction (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Asia-Oceania Biotechnology 1990 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Actinoplanetes and Maduromycetes, Actinomycetes 1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - International Marine Biotechnology Vol. I 1991 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - International Marine Biotechnology Vol. II 1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Controlling Biotechnology Risks: A Holistic Approach to Safety and Environmental Protection 1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Screening for Therapeutic Drugs Using Automated Assays 1993 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 1993 Cleanroom Management (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - 1995 Fungi: An Introduction to Isolation and Taxonomy (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - 2000 Predictive Medicine, Gene Expression Microarrays, Drug Discovery, Prokayotic Expression (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - 2001 Protemics (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV.D. Joint, 1961, n.d.; 6 items (2 folders)
    Programs, reports and paper arranged by meeting
    - American Institute for Biological Sciences, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Botanical Society, n.d (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV.E. Local Chapters, 1951-1988; 75 items (.25 linear feet)
    Agendas, minutes, reports, correspondence and memos arranged by section name.
    - Chicago 1959, 1967-1969, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Indiana 1988 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Metropolitan 1970, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - New England 1973-1976, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Washington 1951- 1960 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Floppy Disk 1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Series V. Publications, 1951-2000; 500 items (10 linear feet)
  Journals, newsletters, programs, abstracts, and pamphlets organized into three sub-series: Journals and Newsletters, Conference, Workshop and Meeting Materials, and Special and Miscellaneous Publications.
  - Subseries V.A. Journals and Newsletters, 1951-2000; 8.25 linear feet
    Printed materials arranged by title and then in date order.
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 1-5 (Box 31)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 6-10 (Box 32)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 11-15 (Box 33)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 16-18 (Box 34)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 19-20 (Box 35)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol.21-23 (Box 36)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 24-25 (Box 37)
    - Developments in Industrial Microbiology Vol. 26-29, 32 (Box 38)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology Newsletter Vol.1 (No. 1-4) – Vol.4 (No. 1-4) (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology Newsletter Vol. 5 (No. 1, 3),Vol. 6 (No. 1, 2), Vol. 7 (No. 1-3), Vol. 8 (No. 1-2) (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology Newsletter Vol. 11 (No. 1-4), Vol. 12 (No.1-3), Vol. 13 (No. 1-3), Vol.14 (No. 1-3), Vol. 15(1-4) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology Newsletter Vol. 16 (No. 1,2,4), Vol. 17 (No. 1-4), Vol. 18 (No.1-4), Vol. 19 (No. 1-5) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology Newsletter Vol. 20 (No. 1-5), Vol. 21 (No. 1-5), Vol. 22 (No. 1, 3,4) (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 23 (No. 1-6) (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 24 (No. 4,6) (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 25 (No. 1-6) (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 26 (No. 1-5) (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 27 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 28 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 29 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 30 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 31 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 32 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 33 (No. 1-4) (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 34 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 35 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 36 (No. 1-6) (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 37 (No. 1-6) (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 38 (No. 1-6) (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 39 (No.6) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 40 (No. 1-6) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 41 (No. 1-6) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 42 (No. 1-6) (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 43 (No. 1, 3-6) (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 44 (No. 1,3-6) (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 45 (No. 1-6) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 46 (No. 1-6) (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 47 (No. 1-6) (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 48 (No. 1-6) (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 49 (No. 1-6) (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Society of Industrial Microbiology News Vol. 50 (No. 1-6) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 1 (No. 1-3) (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 1 (No. 4-6) (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 1 (No. 4-6) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 2 (No. 1-5) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 3 (No. 1-6) (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 4 (No. 3), Vol. 6 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 7 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 8 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 9 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 10 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 11 (No. 1-4) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 12 (No. 1-6) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 13 (No. 1-6) (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 14 (No. 1-6) (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 15 (No. 1-6) (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 16 (No. 1-6) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 17 (No. 1-6) (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 18 (No. 1-6) (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 19 (No. 1-6) (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 20 (No. 1-6) (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Journal of Industrial Microbiology Vol. 21-Vol. 26 (Box 47)
  - Subseries V.B. Conferences, Workshops and Meeting Materials, 1990-2000; 30 items (1 linear foot)
    Programs, abstracts, conference papers and handouts arranged by type of program and then in date order.
    - Annual Meeting Programs and Abstracts 1992-1995, 1997-2000 Conference and Workshop Program and Annual Meeting Programs and Abstracts 1992-1995, 1997-2000 Conference and Workshop Program and Abstracts (Box 48)
    - Conference materials 1991, 1999, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Validation of Automated Systems in the Pharmaceutical Industry 1984 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Biotechnology: GMPs, Regulatory Concerns and Common Sense (Part 1-4) (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Biotechnology: GMPs, Regulatory Concerns and Common Sense (Part 5-7) 1990 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Validation, Design and Start-up of Biotechnology Plants 1991 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Development of Cell Culture Biopharmaceuticals: Manufacturing and Control 1994 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Subseries V.C. Special Publications and Miscellanea, 1959-1982; 120 items (.5 linear feet)
    Printed materials, correspondence, reports, and contracts arranged by subject and then in date order.
    - Special Publication No. 1- 4 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Special Publication No. 5 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Special Publication No. 6 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Contract Agreements 1959-1962 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Newsletter Editor 1965-1976 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Reprint and Page Charges 1959 – 1982 (Box 50, Folder 6)
- Series VI. Affiliated Organizations and Ephemera, 1967-1989; 150 items (.25 linear feet)
  Correspondence, member list and ephemera arranged by subject.
  - Proclamation, Poster, Plaque 1982 – 1989 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science/Correspondence: 1967/8-1975/9 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - American Institute of Biological Science/ Correspondence: 1968/1-1975/9 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Membership: American Institute of Biological Science 1982/3 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University/ Correspondence: 1970 - 2002 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University/ Accession Records and Inventories (Box 51, Folder 6)